Okay, so we started this off by saying
we wanted to have this number here and
we wanted it to increment every time we
visited the page. So
if we come over here, um, how would we
actually accomplish that? Well, we would
need to access the local storage object.
Um,
so I could say local storage dot set
item
and then I could say page visit count
and then I could set that to one.
But the problem is this will set it to
one every single time the page loads.
What I want to do is I want to increase
it if it exists. And if it doesn't
exist, then I want to set it to one.
Well, how could we do that? Well, if we
go back over and visit our page and I
say local storage.get item and I try and
get an item that doesn't exist like blah
blah blah.
If I hit enter, it returns null. So what
I can do is I can see if an item exists
by trying to access it. So I could say
if
local storage.get item page visit count.
So what I'm saying is if the page visit
count exists
then I want to do something otherwise
I want to
create page visit count and set it equal
to one. So
it's going to see if page visit count
exists because it's going to run this
function. If it returns null it's going
to go straight to false. If it returns
something then it's going to come in
here into this true. So what I can do is
I can say let um
visit count equal and then I've got to
convert it to a number. So I'll say
local storage.get get item and we'll get
page visit count
and then um I'll say visit count++
to increment it one and then I'll say
local storage set item page
visit count and I want to set it equal
to the visit count.
Once that's done,
I want to log
the visit count.
So if I save that and I come here, I get
null the first time I visit the page.
Null again, which means I have done
something wrong. Let's look through
this. Oh, it's because it's called page
visit count.
So I'll save it and I'll come over and
it says I visited this page five times.
If I reload, I've now visited 6 7 8 9
10. And that's because we're going into
local storage, accessing the value if it
exists and running our code. Um, let's
get rid of that value. So, you can come
over here and click on page visit count
and delete it. And now, if we come to
our console and reload, it says because
the key didn't exist, it went and
created the key and says we visited this
page one time. If we reload, we visited
two times. If we reload, we visited
three times. And that's how you can use
local storage to persist information um
between page reloads.